MkvDrama.Org
MkvDrama.Org
Episode 12
12화
Is that Mr. Jong in the front carriage?
앞 마차에 있는 저 종씨인가요?
Wait.
잠깐만요.
Junior Wu, how can I help you?
우 후배님, 제가 무엇을 도와드릴까요?
Mistress, you are a very busy woman.
여주인님, 당신은 정말 바쁜 여자이군요.
I sent invitations several times.
여러 번 초대장을 보냈어요
But you didn't respond.
하지만 당신은 응답하지 않았습니다.
You must be joking.
농담하는 게 틀림없어요.
I am a married woman.
나는 기혼 여성입니다.
It is inappropriate to meet you.
당신을 만나는 것은 부적절합니다.
You can go directly to your husband.
남편한테 직접 가셔도 돼요
If you need it.
당신이 필요하다면.
You and I have something to talk about.
당신과 나는 할 얘기가 있어요.
Like that maid in the servant’s residence.
종 거주지의 그 하녀처럼요.
I don't know
모르겠어요.
Which maid?
어느 하녀?
Mu Yao.
무 야오.
So you are talking about her.
그래서 당신은 그녀에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
in fact
사실은
That person will be my husband's concubine.
그 사람은 내 남편의 첩이 될 거야
next month.
다음 달.
You are such a forgiving woman.
당신은 정말 용서하는 여자예요.
What is it, attitude has changed
뭐야, 태도가 바뀌었어
Because I won't cooperate with you?
내가 너한테 협조하지 않겠다고 해서?
how did you know?
어떻게 알았어?
What was I supposed to do?
내가 뭘 하려고 했는데?
Rather than wasting my time and energy
나에게 시간과 에너지를 낭비하기보다는
Turn your attention to someone else.
다른 사람에게 관심을 돌리십시오.
Ultimately, the ball is in her court.
결국 공은 그녀의 코트에 있습니다.
If that person is really interested in you
그 사람이 정말로 당신에게 관심이 있다면
Should I solve the problem alone?
그 문제를 혼자 해결해야 합니까?
Sometimes it's a step late
가끔은 한발 늦는 경우도 있어요
And you may never catch up.
그리고 당신은 결코 따라잡지 못할 수도 있습니다.
What do you know?
당신은 무엇을 알 수 있습니까?
You requested Mu Yao.
무야오를 요청하셨습니다
You went to a feast, right?
향연에 갔지, 그렇지?
If you really care about her
당신이 그녀를 정말로 걱정한다면
Ask her what she thinks of you.
그녀가 당신에 대해 어떻게 생각하는지 물어보세요.
Otherwise, no matter how hard you work
그렇지 않으면 아무리 열심히 일해도
It would be in vain.
그것은 헛된 일이 될 것이다.
what makes you talk
무엇이 당신을 말하게 만드는가
Will my efforts be in vain?
내 노력이 헛되지 않을까요?
You and Mu Yao have only met a few times.
당신과 무야오는 겨우 몇 번 만났어요
And he doesn't like you.
그리고 그 사람은 당신을 좋아하지 않아요.
Why are you so obsessed with her?
왜 그렇게 그녀에게 집착하는 걸까요?
Sometimes despite what has already happened
때로는 이미 일어난 일에도 불구하고
It's up to us to change the outcome.
결과를 바꾸는 것은 우리에게 달려 있습니다.
You don't have to follow a set path.
정해진 길을 따를 필요는 없습니다.
Woo-kyung, think about what I said.
우경님, 제가 한 말을 생각해 보세요.
If you're still in town next month,
다음 달에도 아직 시내에 계시다면
Sure
물론이죠
To attend the wedding banquet.
결혼식 연회에 참석하기 위해.
I will leave.
나는 떠날 것이다.
let's go.
갑시다.
Is he a junior lord of the Wu family?
우 가문의 후배 영주인가?
Do you really like Mu Yao?
정말 무야오를 좋아하나요?
I think so.
그런 것 같아요.
Otherwise, why is he still thinking about her?
그렇지 않으면 왜 그는 아직도 그녀에 대해 생각하고 있습니까?
After so many years?
그렇게 오랜 세월이 흐른 뒤에?
childhood unrequited love
어린 시절의 짝사랑
In the end, it's the most unforgettable thing.
결국 가장 잊혀지지 않는 것입니다.
Did it take that long?
그렇게 오랜 세월이 걸렸나요?
Did they know each other before?
그들은 이전에 서로를 알았나요?
master...
주인...
The bell garden is wonderful.
종의 정원은 훌륭합니다.
There are birds here too
여기에는 새도 있다
I can speak like a human.
사람처럼 말할 수 있어요.
Come down here.
여기로 내려오세요.
He told me about his plans
그는 자신의 계획에 대해 나에게 말했다
Because he wanted to work with me.
왜냐하면 그 사람이 나와 함께 일하고 싶어 했기 때문이죠.
This parrot made four people angry.
이 앵무새는 네 사람을 화나게 했습니다.
What an annoying pet.
정말 짜증나는 애완 동물입니다.
Why not let him take Mu Yao?
그가 Mu Yao를 데려가도록 놔두지 않겠습니까?
He can't take her.
그는 그녀를 데려갈 수 없습니다.
That is a fateful outcome for him.
그것이 그에게 있어서 운명적인 결과이다.
I told him this.
나는 그에게 이렇게 말했다.
Because I wanted that person to accept this reality.
그 사람이 이 현실을 받아들이길 바랐기 때문이다.
And stop being a fool
그리고 그만 바보로 만들어
While I was immersed in their stories.
그들의 이야기에 푹 빠져있는 동안.
Why did you suddenly come to me?
갑자기 왜 나한테 왔어?
Did you find out anything else?
또 뭔가 알아냈어?
This is a gift for Concubine Mu.
이건 후궁 무를 위한 선물이에요
From Your Majesty.
전하로부터.
Congratulations, Master.
축하해요, 마스터.
concubine?
첩?
Thank you, Manager Gao.
감사합니다, 가오 청지기님.
All gifts and orders have been delivered
선물과 주문을 모두 배송했습니다
From Your Majesty.
전하로부터.
I will leave.
나는 떠날 것이다.
Thank you, Manager Gao.
감사합니다, 가오 청지기님.
You went to the servant's garden yesterday.
당신은 어제 종의 정원에 갔었습니다.
And today His Majesty wants me
그리고 오늘 전하께서 나를 원하십니다
Take Mu Yao as your concubine.
무야오를 첩으로 삼아라.
What are you trying to do?
무엇을 하려고 하시나요?
I just did what you wanted to do.
나는 단지 당신이 하고 싶은 일을 했을 뿐입니다.
Why are you still not satisfied?
왜 아직도 만족하지 못하시나요?
Do you know what you are doing?
당신은 당신이 무엇을하고 있는지 알고 있습니까?
Didn't you declare that?
그렇게 선언하지 않았나요?
Was Mu Yao your girl?
Mu Yao가 당신 여자였나요?
I gave you what you wanted.
나는 당신이 원하는 것을주었습니다.
Why are you mad at me?
왜 나한테 화를 내는 거야?
When did you start?
언제부터 시작했어요?
Could you please think about me?
나에 대해 생각 좀 해 주실래요?
are you thinking
당신은 생각을하고 있습니까
Concubine's location
첩의 위치
Isn't that enough for her?
그녀에게는 충분하지 않나요?
Why don't I let her take my place?
그녀가 내 자리를 대신하게 놔두는 게 어때요?
Didn't I say I was a giver?
내가 주는 사람이라고 하지 않았나요?
I can step away. I don't care.
나는 물러날 수 있다. 나는 상관하지 않는다.
I know what you want to do.
나는 당신이 무엇을 하고 싶은지 알고 있습니다.
Are you really behind this?
정말 이 일의 배후에 당신이 있나요?
Who else could it be?
또 누구일까요?
If I were your concubine, would you think so?
내가 첩이라면 그렇게 생각하나요?
can you control me
네가 나를 조종할 수 있겠어?
Mu Yao, you have always been smart.
Mu Yao, 당신은 항상 똑똑했어요
But why has it become denser now?
그런데 왜 지금은 촘촘해졌나요?
Who are the easy targets for bullying?
괴롭힘을 당하기 쉬운 표적은 누구입니까?
Maid or concubine?
하녀인가 첩인가?
So are you trying to humiliate me?
그래서 나한테 모욕감을 주려는 거야?
By taking me as your concubine?
나를 첩으로 삼아서?
Think whatever you want.
원하는대로 생각하십시오.
I know you don't believe me
당신이 나를 믿지 않는다는 걸 알아요
But I really have no thoughts right now.
그런데 지금은 정말 아무 생각도 없어
Competing with you.
당신과 경쟁하는 것.
Otherwise I won't give up. Yes?
그렇지 않으면 나는 포기하지 않을 것입니다. 그렇죠?
You can watch out for me.
당신은 나를 조심할 수 있습니다.
I don't care.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
Anyway, you'll see that I don't mean to be bad.
어쨌든, 내가 나쁘다는 뜻은 아니라는 걸 알게 될 거예요.
Teacher, where are you going?
선생님, 어디로 가시나요?
???Let’s leave first. ???teacher.
???먼저 떠나자. ???선생님.
You can run, but you can't hide.
도망칠 수는 있지만 숨을 수는 없습니다.
Words got out.
말이 나왔습니다.
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Tell me please! What should I do?
말해 주세요! 어떻게 해야 하나요?
My sister is smart.
내 여동생은 똑똑해요.
She will find a way.
그녀는 방법을 찾을 것입니다.
Go ahead and try it. let's go.
어서 해봐요. 갑시다.
Is there no concubine wedding?
첩의 결혼식은 없나요?
Why?
그 이유는 무엇입니까?
It is a rule inherited from our ancestors.
그것은 조상으로부터 물려받은 규칙이다.
So can he wear a wedding dress?
그러면 그 사람은 웨딩드레스를 입을 수 있나요?
concubine
첩
You can only wear a pink wedding dress.
핑크색 웨딩드레스만 입을 수 있어요.
Are there any exceptions?
예외가 있나요?
no!
아니요!
furthermore
게다가
The concubine can only enter through the side door.
첩은 옆문으로만 들어갈 수 있다
And they must provide tea to the hostess
그리고 그들은 여주인에게 차를 제공해야 합니다
Before the whole process is over.
모든 과정이 끝나기 전에.
I didn't know there were so many rules.
규칙이 이렇게 많은지 몰랐어요.
You come from a prestigious family.
당신은 명문가 출신이군요
And Butler Hua has never taken a concubine.
그리고 버틀러 화(Butler Hua)는 첩을 취한 적이 없습니다
So it makes sense that you don't know.
그래서 당신이 모른다는 것이 합리적입니다.
we can't break the rules
우리는 규칙을 어길 수 없어
to protect honor
명예를 지키기 위해
From a wealthy and powerful family.
부유하고 강력한 가족의.
Do you have any other questions, ma’am?
다른 질문 있으신가요, 여주인님?
well...
잘...
A wedding reception is okay, right?
결혼식 피로연은 괜찮죠?
Wedding reception?
결혼식 피로연?
yes.
예.
It's your choice, mistress.
그것은 당신의 선택입니다, 여주인.
Who prepared my wedding?
누가 내 결혼식을 준비했나요?
Deacon Ji.
지 집사.
Tell him to duplicate what he did before
그에게 이전에 했던 일을 복제하라고 말하세요
Invite guests from the same group.
같은 그룹의 손님을 초대하세요.
what?
무엇?
And ditch the ritual of serving tea.
그리고 차를 대접하는 의식을 버리십시오.
this is...
이것은...
OK.
괜찮은.
She didn't argue with me today.
그녀는 오늘 나와 논쟁하지 않았습니다.
Mistress, you were so passionate.
여주인님, 너무 열정적이셨어요.
People who don't know may think this way.
모르는 사람들은 이렇게 생각할 수도 있겠네요
You are the one getting married.
당신은 결혼하는 사람입니다.
Maid Li trained herself.
하녀 리가 자신을 훈련시켰습니다
To not panic even under stress
스트레스 속에서도 당황하지 않기 위해
Otherwise you will be the death of her.
그렇지 않으면 당신은 그녀의 죽음이 될 것입니다.
Lady, I’m going back to work.
여주야, 나 다시 일하러 갈게.
Blind servant! Didn't you see me?
눈먼 종아! 나를 못 봤나요?
???I will kill you ???Teacher.
???죽여버리겠어 ???선생님.
???We are in a bell residence. ???this is...
???저희는 종 거주지에 있습니다. ???이것은...
Master Hwayoung, are you okay?
화영스승님, 괜찮으세요?
My hands were tired
손이 피곤했어요
And I never noticed you coming like this.
그리고 나는 당신이 이런 식으로 오는 것을 눈치 채지 못했습니다.
It's you. me...
당신이에요. 나...
Teacher, that person will soon become your concubine.
선생님, 그 사람은 곧 스승님의 첩이 될 거예요.
The news spread so quickly.
그 소식은 너무나 빨리 퍼졌습니다.
But I didn't serve tea
하지만 난 차를 대접하지 않았어
So I'm still a housekeeper.
그래서 난 아직 가정부야.
Teacher Hwa, why are you in such a hurry?
화선생님, 왜 그렇게 서두르시나요?
I came to see my sister.
나는 내 여동생을 만나러 왔습니다.
The hostess didn't go out today
오늘 여주인은 나가지 않았어
So she should stay at home.
그러니 그녀는 자기 집에 있어야 해요.
Should I lead the way?
내가 길을 안내해야 합니까?
I think that would be good. let's go.
그거 좋을 것 같아요. 갑시다.
We won't bother you. I know the way.
우리는 당신을 괴롭히지 않을 것입니다. 나는 길을 알고 있다.
Teacher, please go.
선생님, 가세요.
Teacher, we have to go.
선생님, 우리 가봐야 해요.
Stay focused.
집중하세요.
Don't forget what we are here for today.
오늘 우리가 무엇을 위해 여기에 있는지 잊지 마세요.
right...
오른쪽...
Hostess, here is the guest list.
여주인님, 손님 명단은 여기 있습니다.
Thank you, Deacon Ji.
고마워요, 지집사님.
Send invitations
초대장 보내기
To everyone on the list.
목록에 있는 모든 사람에게.
Yes, mistress.
네, 여주인님.
Lady, if there is anything else
여주야, 또 다른 일이 있다면
Ask me anytime.
언제든지 저한테 물어보세요.
I am leaving to get ready.
나는 준비를 하러 떠난다.
Did you get enough sleep?
잠은 충분히 잤나요?
I didn't sleep.
나는 잠을 자지 않았다.
I was just distracted.
나는 단지 주의가 산만해졌을 뿐이다.
Are you ready?
준비하고 있나요?
For the wedding reception next month?
다음 달 결혼식 피로연을 위해?
She is just a concubine.
그녀는 단지 첩일 뿐입니다.
I don't think you need it
내 생각엔 너한테는 필요 없을 것 같아
To do too much.
너무 많은 일을 하려고.
When I got here this morning
오늘 아침에 여기 왔을 때
I ran to the maid
나 그 하녀한테 달려갔어
But I didn't recognize her until I started talking to her.
하지만 내가 그녀와 이야기를 나누기 전까지는 그녀를 알아보지 못했습니다.
Isn't that the person I saw?
내가 본 그 사람 아닌가?
Does it come from master's studies?
석사 공부에서 나오나요?
I spoke, but you did not listen.
내가 말했지만 당신은 듣지 않았습니다.
Look what happened.
무슨 일이 일어났는지 보세요.
she got what she wanted
그녀는 원하는 것을 얻었습니다
And made you work too hard
그리고 너를 너무 열심히 일하게 만들었어
To prepare for the wedding feast.
결혼식 잔치를 준비하기 위해.
Why don't you just pretend to be sick?
그냥 아픈 척 하는 게 어때?
Do you let someone else do it for you?
다른 사람이 대신하게 놔두나요?
Leave this difficult task to my brother-in-law.
이 어려운 일을 내 처남에게 맡겨라
Then he will know the difficulties you are facing.
그러면 그는 당신이 직면하고 있는 어려움을 알게 될 것입니다.
Got another problem?
또 문제가 생겼나요?
no.
아니요.
no!
아니요!
I came to see you because I missed you.
보고 싶어서 만나러 왔어요.
if everything is ok
모든 것이 괜찮다면
you won't say or do anything
넌 말하거나 행동하지 않을 거야
Like an ordinary person.
평범한 사람처럼.
Tell me please.
말해 주세요.
What did you do
뭐 했어
Are you trying to make my father angry again?
우리 아버지를 또 화나게 하려고?
You are really smart.
당신은 정말 똑똑해요.
I can't hide anything from you.
나는 당신에게 아무것도 숨길 수 없습니다.
It's not a big problem.
그것은 큰 문제가 아니다.
I gave one of my concubines to someone.
나는 내 첩 중 하나를 누군가에게주었습니다.
and?
그리고?
Yeah, it's not a big deal at all.
예, 전혀 큰 문제가 아닙니다.
I'm exhausted from preparing for the banquet.
연회 준비로 인해 지쳤어요
These few days.
요 며칠.
Can't I just get to the point?
요점만 말씀드리면 안 될까요?
If all you did was
당신이 한 일이 전부였다면
give someone a concubine
누군가에게 첩을 주다
You don't have to come to me.
당신은 나에게 올 필요가 없습니다.
It's really about women.
정말 여자에 관한 것입니다.
OK. Because you have nothing to say
괜찮은. 넌 할 말이 없으니까
You can go back now.
이제 돌아가셔도 됩니다.
I'm busy. I don't have time for you.
나는 바쁘다. 나는 당신을 위한 시간이 없습니다.
OK. I will tell you the truth.
괜찮은. 나는 당신에게 진실을 말할 것입니다.
But can you say something nice for me?
하지만 나에게 좋은 말 한 마디 해주실 수 있나요?
In front of my parents?
우리 부모님 앞에서?
They always listen to you.
그들은 항상 당신의 말을 듣습니다.
Tell me please
말해 주세요
And I will decide if I want to do it for you.
그리고 내가 당신을 위해 그 일을 할지 결정할 것입니다.
i am telling you
나는 당신에게 말하고있다
everything in my house
우리 집에 있는 모든 것
It's high quality.
고품질입니다.
You don't like her? are you okay.
당신은 그녀를 좋아하지 않습니까? 괜찮아요.
There will be more.
더 많은 것이 있을 것입니다.
There are better things out there.
더 좋은 것들이 있습니다.
Go ahead and try it. Let's drink.
어서 해봐요. 마시자.
It's a one shot.
원샷이야.
BB-Beauty, don’t go.
BB-뷰티, 가지 마세요.
Who do you call ‘beauty’?
당신은 누구를 '미인'이라고 부르나요?
I thought about it
나는 생각했다
There were many beautiful women here.
여기에는 아름다운 여성들이 많이 있었습니다.
Isn't it there?
거기 있지 않습니까?
But I just saw a woman.
그런데 방금 한 여자를 봤어.
Someone slightly above average.
평균보다 약간 높은 사람.
And you know what?
그리고 그거 알아?
She ran away.
그녀는 도망갔습니다.
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
if you want her
당신이 그녀를 원한다면
Just take it later.
그냥 나중에 데려가세요.
Sir, this is the 19th concubine he just took.
선생님, 저 사람이 방금 데려간 19번째 첩입니다.
Which one?
어느 것?
Person who purchased
구매하신 분
And at first she was your maid.
그리고 처음에는 당신의 하녀였어요.
What are you talking about? My concubine?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 내 첩?
She is just a maid I bought.
그녀는 내가 사준 하녀일 뿐이다.
Because Brother Wang likes that person.
왕 형제님이 그 사람을 좋아하니까
Just take her with you.
그냥 그녀를 데리고 가세요.
Brother Hua, thank you so much.
화 형제님, 정말 감사합니다.
Are you truly the son of the Hua family?
당신은 과연 화씨 가문의 아들이군요
And I am amazed at your generosity.
그리고 당신의 관대함에 놀랐습니다.
Why are you still here?
왜 아직도 여기에 있나요?
Bring her here.
그녀를 여기로 데려오세요.
well...
잘...
???You... ???I'll do it...
???너... ???내가 할게...
Go ahead and try it. Let's drink.
어서 해봐요. 마시자.
Why hasn't he come yet?
그 사람은 왜 아직 안 왔어요?
I'm so excited.
너무 기대돼요.
my house is big
내 집은 크다
So it will take some time to get here.
그러니 여기 오려면 시간이 좀 걸릴 거예요.
???How rich is he... ???Wait just a moment.
???얼마나 부자인지... ???조금만 기다리세요.
Where is she?
그녀는 어디 있습니까?
say.
말하다.
How dare she!
감히 그녀는!
I will fix her.
나는 그녀를 고칠 것입니다.
???teacher! ???I'll go with you.
???선생님! ???내가 같이 갈게.
Tell me, Qian.
말해봐, 퀴안.
My friend wanted a girl to come into his house.
내 친구는 내 집에 여자가 들어오길 원했어요.
How could I refuse?
내가 어떻게 거절할 수 있겠는가?
But the maid... was ungrateful.
그런데 그 하녀는... 배은망덕했어요.
The moment I lost my mind
정신이 혼미해진 순간
She died after hitting her head on a pillar.
그녀는 기둥에 머리를 부딪쳐 죽었습니다.
She brought bad luck to my house.
그녀는 내 집에 불운을 가져왔습니다.
Actually, I took care of everything.
사실 내가 다 챙겨줬는데
But a maid leaked the incident.
그런데 어떤 하녀가 그 사건을 누설했어요
So now I'm afraid to go home.
그래서 지금은 집에 가기가 두렵습니다.
What do you want me to do?
내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
I guess my father
아무래도 우리 아버지가
You should know this by now
지금쯤이면 이 사실을 알았을 텐데
And he will punish me for this.
그리고 그는 이것에 대해 나를 처벌할 것입니다.
Can you say something nice for me?
나에게 좋은 말 좀 해주실 수 있나요?
In front of him?
그 앞에서?
Then don’t you think he should be punished?
그럼 처벌을 받아야 한다고 생각하지 않나요?
of course.
물론.
Punishment because of the maid?
하녀 때문에 벌을 받는다?
How embarrassing would it be if rumors spread?
만약 소문이 나면 얼마나 당황스러울까요?
Qian, you have no idea.
Qian, 당신은 전혀 모른다.
The maid was once found guilty and sold.
그 하녀는 한때 유죄 판결을 받고 팔렸습니다.
I shouldn't have bought him
내가 그 사람을 사지 말았어야 했는데
Out of sympathy.
동정심에서.
Of course, people like her deserve it.
물론이죠, 그녀 같은 사람은 그럴 자격이 있어요
And they can't be good.
그리고 그들은 좋을 수 없습니다.
Do you think someone like her deserves it?
그녀 같은 사람이 그럴 자격이 있다고 생각하세요?
yes. Do you know what he made me do?
예. 그 사람이 나한테 무슨 일을 하게 했는지 알아?
Get out!
나가세요!
Kian.
키안.
I've been kinder to you lately
최근에 너한테 더 친절하게 대해줬어
So you think I will?
그래서 내가 그럴 거라고 생각하는 거야?
Could you please take care of this for me?
당신을 위해 이것 좀 처리해 주실래요?
me...
나...
I will never interfere in your private affairs.
나는 결코 당신의 사적인 일에 간섭하지 않습니다.
I thought about it ...
나는 생각했다 ...
I think at least the women in your house
내 생각에는 적어도 당신 집에 있는 그 여자들만은
A social climber and willing to party.
사회적 등반가이자 기꺼이 파티를 열었습니다.
Turns out I was wrong.
내가 틀렸다는 것이 밝혀졌습니다.
You have become so reckless and shameless!
당신은 너무 무모하고 뻔뻔스러워졌습니다!
Mr. Huarongzhou, please come in.
화룽저우 씨, 들어오세요.
Hwa Yong-ju, take my younger brother away.
화용주야, 내 동생을 데려가라
Return to Hua Residence.
Hua Residence로 돌아갑니다.
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
Go and bring Nanfeng here.
가서 난펑을 여기로 데려오세요.
Yes, mistress.
네, 여주인님.
government.
정부.
Nanfeng.
난펑.
I hope you do something for me
나는 당신이 나를 위해 뭔가를 해주기를 바랍니다
And I will be in your debt.
그리고 나는 당신에게 빚을 질 것입니다.
Lady, don’t say that.
여주야, 그런 말 하지 마.
I work for you.
나는 당신을 위해 일합니다.
Tell me whatever you want.
내가 원하는 것은 무엇이든 말해 보세요.
Go to Hua Residence with the men.
남자들과 함께 Hua Residence로 가십시오.
Please tell me those are my instructions.
그게 내 지시라고 말해줘.
Ask the girls at my brother's house
내 동생 집에 있는 여자들에게 물어봐
If any of them want to leave.
그들 중 떠나고 싶은 사람이 있다면.
Those who want to leave
떠나고 싶은 분들
Bring it here.
여기로 가져와.
I will give them enough money
나는 그들에게 충분한 돈을 줄 것이다
To live comfortably for the rest of my life.
남은 생애 동안 편안하게 살기 위해.
you are the master's guard
당신은 마스터의 경비원입니다
So my father probably won't stop you.
그러니 우리 아버지는 아마 당신을 막지 않으실 거예요.
WW-Wait a minute.
WW-잠깐.
What are you going to do?
당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
Do you think you did nothing wrong?
당신은 당신이 잘못한 것이 없다고 생각합니까?
Does the life of a maid mean nothing to you?
가정부의 삶이 당신에게 아무 의미가 없나요?
She is just a slave.
그녀는 단지 노예입니다.
I bought her and her life was mine.
나는 그녀를 샀고 그녀의 생명은 내 것이었습니다.
She wanted to commit suicide.
그녀는 자살하고 싶었습니다.
What can I do about it?
나는 그것에 대해 무엇을 할 수 있습니까?
Is she just a slave?
그녀는 단지 노예인가요?
Aren’t slaves people?
노예는 사람 아닌가요?
Do slaves have no loved ones?
노예에게는 사랑하는 사람이 없습니까?
What happens if this happens to me?
나에게 이런 일이 발생하면 어떻게 되나요?
What if I become a slave?
내가 노예가 된다면?
What happens if I am deported or sold?
추방되거나 팔리면 어떻게 되나요?
Would you say that?
그렇게 말해줄래?
Do I deserve that too?
나도 그럴 자격이 있나요?
Put yourself in her shoes.
그녀의 입장이 되어보세요.
Imagine how much pain it must have been for her family.
그녀의 가족이 얼마나 고통스러웠을지 상상해보세요.
The maid was once a criminal.
그 하녀는 한때 범죄자였습니다.
she was an orphan
그녀는 고아였습니다
And I had no family.
그리고 가족도 없었습니다.
That's why you think
그렇기 때문에 당신은 생각한다
You didn't do anything wrong?
당신은 아무 잘못도 하지 않았나요?
Nanfeng, I will be counting on you.
Nanfeng, 나는 당신을 믿고 있을 것입니다.
please take my sister back
내 동생을 다시 데려가주세요
And tell your father
그리고 아버지한테 말해요
If he still does not discipline his son
만일 그가 아직도 자기 아들을 징계하지 아니하면
I'll do it for him.
내가 그 사람을 위해 할게요.
???Yes, mistress. ???You should be happy
???네, 여주인님. ???기뻐해야지
That you are my brother.
당신이 내 형제라는 걸요.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be able to stand right here.
그렇지 않으면 당신은 지금 이 자리에 온전하게 서 있을 수 없을 것입니다.
Should I make you walk?
널 걷게 해야 하나?
Hua teacher?
후아 선생님?
Has the bergamot scent gone bad?
베르가못 향이 상했나요?
Why does it smell strange?
왜 이상한 향기가 나는 걸까요?
I don't think so.
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않습니다.
Put that away.
그거 치워두세요.
This is a request from the lady.
여주님의 부탁입니다.
Please approve, Butler Whoa.
승인해 주세요, 버틀러 후아.
sulfur.
황.
Take him to Hua Shen's house.
그를 Hua Shen의 집으로 데려가세요.
All right.
알겠습니다.
Please come this way.
이쪽으로 오십시오.
self.
자기.
He just bought a maid.
그는 단지 하녀를 샀을 뿐입니다.
It's not strange at all
전혀 이상한 일이 아니야
But she did a great job with it.
그러나 그녀는 그것으로 큰 일을 해냈습니다.
Why can't she save her brother?
그녀는 왜 동생을 구하지 못하는가?
Because you're embarrassed?
당황해서?
That's right, father. great.
그렇죠, 아버지. 좋아요.
she's too busy with the wedding
그녀는 결혼식 때문에 너무 바빠요
It seems to make her angry quickly.
그녀를 빨리 화나게 만드는 것 같습니다.
???Her... ???Servant.
???그녀... ???서번트.
Bring me a ruler.
나에게 통치자를 가져와.
father! I was wrong!
아버지! 내가 틀렸어!
I won't do it again, Dad.
다시는 그러지 않겠습니다, 아버지.
???yes. He knows... ???Father, I was wrong!
???예. 그 사람은 알고 있어요... ???아버지, 제가 틀렸어요!
Why are you still here?
왜 아직도 여기에 있나요?
Should I get it myself?
제가 직접 받아야 하나요?
All right.
알겠습니다.
Father, I was wrong!
아버지, 제가 틀렸어요!
I won't do it again, Dad.
다시는 그러지 않겠습니다, 아버지.
I won't do it again. Don't beat me!
다시는 안 할 거예요. 구타하지 마세요!
I was wrong, father!
제가 틀렸어요, 아버지!
let's go.
갑시다.
Father, I was wrong!
아버지, 제가 틀렸어요!
father! Stop!
아버지! 멈추다!
father...
아버지...
Guard Nanfeng, you are in a hurry.
경비병 Nanfeng, 당신은 서두르고 있습니다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
I'm dealing with something.
나는 뭔가를 다루고 있어요
On behalf of the mistress.
여주인을 대신해서.
Is this an issue that has been a hot topic?
많이 화제가 되었던 문제인가
Is it related to Butler Hua's son?
버틀러 후아(Butler Hua)의 아들과 관련이 있나요?
yes.
예.
Did you send him to jail?
그 사람을 감옥에 보냈나요?
no. I just sent him to Hua Residence.
아니요. 방금 그를 Hua Residence로 보냈습니다.
Then Butler Hua will decide what to do with him.
그러면 버틀러 후아(Butler Hua)가 그에게 무엇을 할지 결정할 것입니다.
well.
글쎄요.
Get back to work. I won't hold you back.
다시 일하세요. 나는 당신을 붙잡지 않을 것입니다.
The hostess, Nanfeng, is back.
여주인, Nanfeng이 돌아왔습니다.
He returned with four young women.
그는 네 명의 젊은 여성을 데리고 돌아왔습니다.
At Hua Residence.
후아 레지던스에서.
They are now in the outer court.
그들은 지금 바깥뜰에 있습니다.
people believe
사람들은 믿는다
A wife must listen to her husband.
아내는 남편의 말을 들어야 한다는 것입니다.
There aren't many women with courage
용기 있는 여자는 많지 않아요
To combat that stigma.
그 오명에 맞서기 위해.
Give everyone some money
각자에게 돈을 좀 줘
And help them prepare to leave.
그리고 그들이 떠날 준비를 하도록 도와주세요.
Yes, mistress.
네, 여주인님.
Peach blossoms have bloomed in the backyard.
뒷마당에 복숭아꽃이 피었습니다.
Do you want to go there to relax your mind?
마음의 휴식을 위해 그곳에 가고 싶나요?
It's a good idea to go out for a walk.
산책하러 나가는 것이 좋습니다.
I picked too many.
나는 너무 많이 골랐다.
Enough to make wine
와인을 만들기에 충분해요
And peach blossom cake.
그리고 복숭아꽃 케이크.
Let's go back.
돌아가자.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
There is no need to apologize, Master.
사과하실 필요는 없습니다, 마스터.
I know your orders.
나는 전하의 명령을 알고 있다
It has nothing to do with you.
당신과 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Maybe I misled Hua Qian.
어쩌면 내가 Hua Qian을 잘못 인도했을 수도 있습니다.
are you okay. I will not make you a concubine.
괜찮아요. 나는 당신을 첩으로 만들지 않을 것입니다.
But I can't divorce him yet.
하지만 아직은 그 사람과 이혼할 수 없어요.
If you do not agree, you can decline.
동의하지 않으시면 거절하시면 됩니다
And I will ask my mistress to cancel her order.
그리고 나는 내 여주인에게 그녀의 명령을 취소하라고 요청할 것입니다.
I know you are kind.
나는 당신이 친절하다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
but...
하지만...
this is what i want
이것이 내가 원하는거야.
It seems that some people are already here.
이미 여기에 와 있는 사람들도 있는 것 같습니다.
government.
정부.
are you okay. Let's go back.
괜찮아요. 돌아가자.
Hwa Yong-ju, are you tall?
화용주 씨, 키가 컸나요?
He was almost the same height as me.
나랑 키가 거의 똑같았어
When I joined last year
작년에 합류했을 때
But now I think he's a little taller than me.
그런데 지금은 나보다 키가 좀 큰 것 같아요.
Guard Hua is still growing.
Guard Hua는 여전히 성장하고 있습니다.
I think he's much taller.
내 생각엔 그 사람 키가 훨씬 더 클 것 같아요.
But his face still looks like a boy.
하지만 그의 얼굴은 여전히 ​​소년 같다.
Look at him. That person is too thin
그를 봐. 그 사람 너무 말랐어
But your face is round like a baby
근데 얼굴이 아기처럼 둥그스름해
That makes him look younger.
그게 그를 더욱 젊어 보이게 만든다.
It's a round face
동그란 얼굴이 맞네요
It will make people look younger.
사람들을 젊어 보이게 만들어 줄 거예요.
I have to say that those chubby cheeks are adorable.
그 통통한 볼이 사랑스럽다고 해야 할까요.
I can't help but want to pinch that cheek.
그 뺨을 꼬집고 싶을 수밖에 없어요
And take a bite.
그리고 한입 먹어보세요.
Rest assured. I'm not going to start chipping away at you.
안심하다. 나는 당신을 조금씩 갉아먹기 시작하지 않을 것입니다.
???Please come this way. ???congratulation.
???이쪽으로 오십시오. ???축하해요.
???Come on in. ???congratulations.
???들어오세요. ???축하합니다.
???Thank you... ???Please come in.
???고맙습니다... ???들어오세요.
???You can put it here. ???Here you are.
???여기에 넣어도 됩니다. ???여기 있어요.
???Congratulations... ???This way.
???축하합니다... ???이쪽입니다.
Please come this way.
이쪽으로 오십시오.
Store owner Ryu.
가게 주인 류.
???congratulation. ???thank you...
???축하해요. ???감사합니다...
Congratulations, Yeoju!
여주야, 축하해.
thank you Please come.
감사합니다. 오세요.
Look at her.
그녀를 봐.
She prepared a wedding banquet
그녀는 결혼식 연회를 준비했습니다
For a concubine.
첩을 위해.
I don't really understand her.
나는 그녀를 정말로 이해하지 못합니다.
What else could there be?
또 무엇이 있을까요?
???To show her generosity! ???thank you.
???그녀의 관대함을 보여주기 위해! ???감사합니다.
I've never seen someone do this much work
누군가 이렇게 많은 일을 하는 건 처음 봤어
When a husband takes a concubine.
남편이 첩을 맞이할 때.
It's true.
그것은 사실이다.
She really is a “good wife.”
그녀는 정말 "좋은 아내"입니다.
I'll tell my daughter not to pretend.
딸한테는 척하지 말라고 할게
To be someone other than her.
그녀가 아닌 누군가가 되는 것.
thank you
감사합니다.
A girl who grew up in a rich and powerful family.
부유하고 강력한 가문에서 자란 소녀
Always look at the bigger picture.
항상 더 큰 그림을 봅니다.
Think about your identity
당신의 정체성을 생각해 보세요
Before talking about someone behind their back.
누군가의 뒤에서 이야기하기 전에.
What do girls from commoner families have?
평민 집안의 소녀들은 무엇을 가지고 있습니까?
Are you trying to compare me to that person?
그 사람이랑 비교하려고?
Were you here too, Mrs. Hua?
당신도 여기에 계셨나요, Hua 부인?
If my memory serves me right
내 기억이 나에게 맞는다면
Your husband was just transferred here.
당신 남편이 방금 여기로 전근됐어요
From a small town.
작은 마을 출신.
Just a butler from a lowly family.
그냥 천한 집안의 집사.
Of course you would
당연히 당신은 그럴 것입니다
That's presumptuous and rude.
그건 주제넘고 무례한 일이다.
Fahrenheit...
화씨...
My husband is in charge of procurement.
남편이 조달을 담당하고 있습니다.
It's for the Zhong family, right?
Zhong 가족을 위한 거죠, 그렇죠?
Still an errand boy
아직도 심부름꾼이네
After working for many years.
수년 동안 일한 후에.
Shouldn’t you ask yourself why?
왜 그런지 스스로에게 물어봐야 하지 않나요?
You are right and I am wrong, Mrs. Hua.
당신 말이 맞고 나는 틀렸습니다, Hua 부인.
I will remember you.
나는 당신을 기억할 것입니다.
Please don't let me hear any more gossip
더 이상 험담을 듣지 못하게 해주세요
And be careful.
그리고 조심하세요.
???yes. ???Please come this way.
???예. ???이쪽으로 오십시오.
I don't care what my daughter does
내 딸이 뭘 하든 상관없어
She is the only daughter of the Hua family.
그녀는 화씨 가문의 외동딸이다
And Mr. Jong’s wife.
그리고 종 선생님의 아내.
Him and you lowly women
그와 너희 비천한 여자들
It's not the same.
동일하지 않습니다.
long time no see.
오랜만이에요.
let's go.
갑시다.
???congratulation. ???congratulation.
???축하해요. ???축하해요.
???Please come this way. ???Please come.
???이쪽으로 오십시오. ???오세요.
please.
제발.
What brings you here, mother?
무슨 일로 여기까지 오셨나요, 어머니?
Look what you did.
당신이 한 일을보세요.
You have brought shame to our family.
당신은 우리 가족에게 수치심을 안겨주었습니다.
Brother...
동생...
There are a lot of people here.
여기에는 많은 사람들이 있습니다.
Go in first, mother.
먼저 들어가세요, 어머니.
Your brother will come too.
네 형도 올 거야.
Keep an eye on him.
그를 계속 지켜보세요.
Kian.
키안.
Everyone present today is of high status.
오늘 참석한 모든 사람은 지위가 높습니다.
act yourself
자신을 행동
And don't bother me anymore.
그리고 더 이상 나를 괴롭히지 마세요.
Don't worry, Kian.
걱정하지 마세요, 키안.
I know what I can and cannot do today.
나는 오늘 내가 할 수 있는 것과 할 수 없는 것을 알고 있다.
Does this mean today will be okay?
오늘은 괜찮을 거라는 뜻인가요?
Still, you won’t change in the future, right?
그래도 넌 앞으로도 변하지 않을 거야?
no. I am a different person now.
아뇨. 저는 이제 달라진 사람이에요.
is it so.
그래요.
I am different now.
나는 이제 다르다.
Qian, you really are a different person now.
Qian, 이제 정말 사람이 달라졌어요.
I will never cause you any trouble again.
다시는 당신에게 문제를 일으키지 않겠습니다.
Concubine Mu, it’s over.
첩 무, 끝났습니다.
wait.
기다리다.
Put this on me.
나한테 이걸 입혀줘.
I don't think this hairpin suits me well.
이 머리핀은 잘 안 어울리는 것 같아
In today's outfit...
오늘 옷차림으로...
are you okay. Just put this on me.
괜찮아요. 그냥 나한테 이것 좀 입혀줘.
Yes, concubine Mu.
응, 후궁 무.
There will be various types of bread.
다양한 빵종류가 있을거에요
And here are some melon seeds. Eat your own food...
그리고 여기 멜론 씨앗도 있어요. 알아서 드세요...
be careful.
조심하세요.
Please help them.
그들에게 도움을 주세요.
???Congratulations, Mistress. ???government.
???축하합니다, 여주인님. ???정부.
The Lord is here. Lord.
주님이 여기 계십니다. 주님.
Lord.
주님.
Have a few more drinks.
몇 잔 더 드세요.
Come on, give it a try...
어서 해봐요...
I'll fill it in for you.
제가 대신 채워드리겠습니다.
???You can't leave. ???Of course not.
???당신은 떠날 수 없습니다. ???당연히 아니지.
Come here and sit with me.
여기로 와서 나와 함께 앉으세요.
Lord.
주님.
???Let’s sit here. ???What are you so happy about?
???여기 앉자. ???뭐가 그렇게 기뻐?
Lord, all the guests have arrived.
주님, 손님이 모두 도착했습니다.
We will guide you to your seat.
자리로 안내해 드리겠습니다.
The wedding is about to begin.
결혼식이 곧 시작됩니다.
Aren't you surprised that I attended?
내가 참석한 것에 놀라지 않았나요?
I am surprised now.
나는 지금 놀랐다.
You haven't answered me yet.
당신은 아직 나에게 대답하지 않았습니다.
What are you so happy about?
뭐가 그렇게 기뻐?
Lord, that's a good question.
주님, 좋은 질문입니다.
Actually I'm not happy
사실 난 행복하지 않아
But in the end it's a happy chance
하지만 결국은 행복한 기회야
So I think it's better to smile.
그러니 웃는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Huaqian
화첸
Are you completely indifferent to my senior now?
지금 내 선배한테 전혀 무관심한 거야?
How can you do that?
어떻게 그럴수있어?
You are thinking too much, Lord.
너무 생각이 많으세요, 주님.
Not required
필요없다
To eliminate the ritual of serving tea.
차를 대접하는 의식을 없애기 위해.
You don’t have to serve me tea.
나에게 차를 대접할 필요는 없습니다.
You're making Mu Yao break the rules
넌 Mu Yao가 규칙을 어기게 만들고 있어
It is inherited from our ancestors.
조상으로부터 물려받은 것입니다.
I only suggest this with good intentions.
나는 단지 좋은 의도로 이것을 제안했을 뿐입니다.
because you don't agree
당신이 동의하지 않으니까
Then observe the ritual of serving tea.
그런 다음 차를 대접하는 의식을 지키십시오.
Now you don't even need to act
이제 넌 굳이 행동할 생각도 안 해
Nothing more calm and noble.
더 이상 차분하고 고결합니다.
What, you don’t like it?
뭐, 마음에 안 드는데?
Then divorce me.
그럼 나랑 이혼해.
Muyao, here is the bracelet.
무야오, 여기 팔찌 있어요.
A little something from me.
나에게서 약간의 것.
Go ahead and try it.
어서 해봐요.
???Go in. ???let's eat.
???들어가. ???먹자.
???Please go in. ???Enjoy.
???들어가세요. ???즐기세요.
???Start eating. ???great.
???식사 시작. ???좋아요.
???Go ahead and try it. ???let's eat.
???어서 해봐요. ???먹자.
Eat as much as you want.
원하는 만큼 드세요.
If you run out of food
음식이 부족할 경우
I'll tell the chef to prepare more.
요리사에게 더 준비하라고 할게요.
???Go ahead and try it. ???Let’s drink.
???어서 해봐요. ???마시자.
???Cheers. ???Go ahead and try it.
???건배. ???어서 해봐요.
please.
제발.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Cheers to Mrs. Hua.
Hua 부인에게 건배합니다.
You don't have to be so polite.
그렇게 예의바르게 행동할 필요는 없습니다.
Go ahead and try it.
어서 해봐요.
Cheers to you.
당신에게 건배.
Eat more.
더 많이 드세요.
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
Try this. It's good.
이 시도. 좋네요.
???government. ???Where is my brother?
???정부. ???내 동생은 어디 있지?
great...
좋아요...
I just saw him walking around in the backyard.
방금 그 사람이 뒷마당에서 돌아다니는 걸 봤어요.
Tell this to the ladies here
여기 아가씨들한테 전해줘
They all come from wealthy families.
모두 부유한 집안 출신이다
And he said he better not move.
그리고 그 사람은 움직이지 않는 게 좋겠다고 하더군요
So that he doesn't upset anyone.
그가 누군가를 화나게 하지 않도록.
Yes, mistress.
네, 여주인님.
Go ahead and try it. One more drink.
어서 해봐요. 한 잔 더.
???sure. ???Go ahead and try it.
???확신하는. ???어서 해봐요.
Thank you to everyone who came today.
오늘 와주신 모든 분들께 감사드립니다.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Hello, Master Hwayoung.
안녕하세요, 화영스승님.
Hello pretty.
안녕 예쁜이.
I am my mistress's maid.
나는 여주인의 하녀입니다.
right. I remember you.
오른쪽. 나는 당신을 기억합니다.
The hostess instructed me to speak.
여주인이 나한테 말하라고 지시했어
The ladies here
여기 아줌마들 말이야
They all come from wealthy and powerful families.
모두 부유하고 강력한 가문 출신이다.
You better not move
움직이지 않는 게 좋을 거야
So as not to offend anyone.
누군가를 화나게하지 않도록.
I'm full.
나는 전체 해요.
I'm just going to stay here and not go anywhere.
난 그냥 여기에 머물고 아무데도 가지 않을 거예요.
Hwang went to buy hangover soup for me.
황은 나를 위해 해장국을 사러 갔습니다.
After the banquet is over
연회가 끝난 후
tell my mom that
우리 엄마한테 그렇게 말해줘
She can come here looking for me.
그녀는 나를 찾으러 여기로 올 수 있어요.
I will leave.
나는 떠날 것이다.
OK.
괜찮은.
Are you going to become Zong Yeran’s concubine?
종예란의 첩이 될 건가요?
yes.
예.
If this isn't what you want, here's what I can do...
이것이 당신이 원하는 것이 아니라면, 제가 할 수 있는 것은...
this is what i want
이것이 내가 원하는거야.
You will regret this.
당신은 이것을 후회할 것입니다.
Let's talk about when you really regret it.
정말 후회할 때 얘기해보자.
junior road
주니어로드
I don't know why you keep coming to me
왜 자꾸 나한테 오는지 모르겠어
But don't come to me again.
하지만 다시는 나에게 오지 마세요.
I'll find someone to catch you
널 잡아줄 사람을 구해올게
Every time I see you.
당신을 볼 때마다.
I told you before
내가 전에 말했잖아
But you forgot.
하지만 당신은 잊어버렸어요.
What motivated you to come to me?
당신이 나에게 온 동기는 무엇입니까?
I swear.
맹세해요.
I fell in love with you at first sight
나는 첫눈에 당신과 사랑에 빠졌습니다
And I can't stop thinking about you.
그리고 당신에 대해 생각하는 것을 멈출 수 없습니다.